Sebastian Velasquez

💌 anse23@hotmail.com | 🔲 +593 987021212 | GitHubsosegon | 🛅 sosegon | 🗫 work sosegon

Summary

Over the years, I have acquired experience in different contexts of computer graphics. I have complimented my knowledge with formal education in the field of artificial intelligence. Currently, I am interested in projects related to machine learning, computer vision, and user experience.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Javascript, Java, Python.

Libraries: OpenCV, Threejs, Nodejs, React. IDEs: Android Studio, Eclipse, Sublime Text.

Version Control Systems: Git.

Databases: MySQL, SQLite. Operating Systems: Linux, Windows. Languages: Spanish, English.

Project Experience

AnkiGame: Design and Implementation

August 2018

A gamified version of the educational tool AnkiDroid. The work required the evaluation of the existing user interface, design of the gamification strategy, and implementation of the solution. The distinctive characteristic of the solution was the inclusion of a casual game as an additional motivational element.

Skin filter: Design and Implementation

November 2017

A Chrome extension that detects and filters human skin in images of websites. The extension is an adaptation of another one, which required to modify and extend the source code to implement computer vision algorithms and probabilistic analysis. The objective of the tool is to protect vulnerable audiences by hiding explicit content.

Remove background: Design and Implementation

July 2016

A desktop application that removes the background from brick imagery. The solution implements machine learning algorithms to analyse the content of the image and extract the important information. It was used to increase the efficiency in the workflow of texture creation.

3D editor application: Developer

May 2016

A web application to design and create objects for 3D printing purposes. The application is intended to be easy-to-use for novice and advanced 3D users. The contribution to the project included the implementation of more than 20 algorithms and specific features for the application, and the process management of a team of six members.

Work Experience

Freelancer: MENTOR & PROJECT REVIEWER, Online

January 2017 - Present

I help students to succeed in machine learning and software development programs. I review their projects, answer their questions, and provide valuable feedback. I use my knowledge and expertise to make corrections, provide suggestions and recommend useful resources.

Freelancer: 3D MODELER, Online

October 2009 - June 2016

I worked in more than 100 projects for several purposes including 3D printing, video games and vehicle modifications. I also edited and created more than 1000 images for several purposes: repetitive textures, portraits, etc. Finally, I made analysis of web pages to increase their performance and visual appearance.

NYQuicksale: 3D DEVELOPER, Online

April 2011 - May 2016

I implemented more than 20 algorithms for 3D manipulation (FFD, Polygon finding, Clipping, Extrusion, Sweep line, Grouping, Unfolding, Bezier curves, etc.), and created the core structure of the web application. I collaborated with a team of six members from different time zones and cultural backgrounds.

Latinmedia SA: SUPPORT ENGINEER, Quito - Ecuador

April 2008 - October 2009

I assembled simulation systems for heavy machinery training, trained customers to operate simulation systems, and created plugins to increase the functionality of several software tools.

Education

Postgraduate

The University of Edinburgh, MSc Artificial Intelligence

Edinburgh - UK | 2018

Undergraduate

Escuela Politécnica Nacional, BS in Electrical Engineering

Quito - Ecuador | 2009

MOOC

Udacity: Machine Learning, Android Development, Mobile Development

Online | 2016

Other

Training on tools for simulation

Montreal - Canadá | 2008

Awards

Scholarship for academic excellence

Escuela Politécnica Nacional, 2004.

Top rated freelancer in Upwork (100% job success)

Online, 2016

Udacity scholarship for academic success

Online, 2016